Animesh Rawat

Frontend Developer

animesh.rawat20@gmail.com

+91 7838436141

Noida, India

Portfolio

GitHub

n <u>LinkedIn</u>



Summary

Web developer with over 6.5 years of experience. A passionate coder with an eye for detail and a focus to produce quality work. Extensive knowledge of web technologies, modern libraries and frameworks.

Professional Skills -

Angular TypeScript CSS Vue JavaScript SASS React HTML

Firebase

Work experience

Rakuten

UI/UX Engineer 06/2020 - present

- Manage team of developers for technical blockers and tasks
- Developed an enterprise application with scalable solutions
- Developed custom and complex web tools related to telecom domain

HCL Technologies

Lead Engineer 09/2018 - 04/2020

- Won Hackathon of Edge team in HCL for solution of reusable Angular component
- Developed web tool for client in HVAC domain with E2E solution

Mobikasa

Frontend Developer 01/2018 - 09/2018

- Developed an E-commerce angular application which was originally built using Shopify framework with a user base of thousands.
- Created a CMS tool for E-commerce app for inventory and order tracking

Tech Mahindra

Software Developer 06/2015 - 01/2018

- Won Hackathon organised by a leading Life Insurance company in Australia.
- Awarded "Best Implementation of new technology in a customer service context".
- Won "Digital Warrior" and "Pat on Back" awards

Education

Sharda University

B.Tech in Electronics and Communications

2011 - 2015

St. Mary's Academy

12th standard in Science

2010 - 2011

St. Mary's Academy

10th standard in Computer

2008 - 2009